Guide to the Veterinary Reprint and Pamphlet Collection, 1865-1950
Veterinary Reprint and Pamphlet Collection, 1865-1950
- W
  - Wedderburn, Alex J. "Report on the extent and character of food and drug adulteration." U. S. Department of Agriculture, Division of Chemistry, Bulletin No. 41, 1894. (Box 5)
  - Wehr, Everett E. "Description of a new genus and species of nematode worm occurring in the northwestern belted kingfisher, with a key to the genera of the subfamily acuariinae." Reprinted from the Proceedings of the United States National Museum, 1931. (Box 5)
  - _______. "A new specied of nematode worm from the sage grouse." Reprinted from the Proceedings of the United States National Museum, 1931. (Box 5)
  - Weiser, Stephen. "Die melasse-futterung." VIII Congres International de Medecine Veterinaire, Budapest, 1905. (Box 5)
  - Weissenberg, Richard. "Flub und bachneunauge (lampetra fluviatillis l. und lampetra planeri bloch), ein morphologisch-biologischer vergleich." Reprinted from Zoolog. Anzeiger, 17 June 1925. (Box 5)
  - Welch, William H. "Adaptation in pathological processes." Reprinted from Science, 28 May 1897. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Preliminary report of investigations concerning the causation of hog cholera." Reprinted from The Johns Hopkins Hospital Bulletin, December 1889. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Bacteriological investigations of diptheria in the United States." Reprinted from The American Journal of the Medical Sciences, October 1894. (Box 5)
  - Wesbrook, F. F. "Beitrag zur immunisirungsfrage." Reprinted from Hygienischen Rundschau, 1894. (Box 5)
  - Whipple, George C. "The water supplies of the New York metropolitan district with special reference to their purification." Reprinted from Journal of the New Englad Water Works Association, 1905. (Box 5)
  - Whitaker, George M. "The milk supply of Boston and other New Englad cities." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Burean of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 20, 1898. (Box 5)
  - White, G. F. and W. E. Dove. "The causation of creeping eruption." Reprinted from The Journal of the American Medical Association, 26 May 1928. (Box 5)
  - White, William Charles. "Natural and artificial cure of tuberculosis." National Tuberculosis Association, Technical Series No. 1, 1925. (Box 5)
  - Wight, J.S. "Some measurements of skulls and heads showing that development, growth and education increase the volume of the anterior parts of the cerebrum-indicated by the masto-frontal angle." (Box 5)
  - Wilder, Burt Green. "American reports upon anatomical nomenclature, 1889-1890. Cornell publication? 5 February 1892. (Box 5)
  - _______. "The anatomical uses of the cat." Reprinted from the New York Medical Journal, October 1879. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Brain-weight, etc." Reprinted from "The gross anatomy of the brain" in Wood's Reference Handbook of the Medical Sciences, n.d. (Box 5)
  - _______. "The desirability and the feasibility on the acquisition of some real and accurate knowledge of the brain by pre-collegiate scholars." Reprinted from Science, 17 December 1897. (Box 5)
  - _______."The dorsal sack, the aulix and the diencephalic flexure." Abstract of address read before the American Neurological Association, 4 June 1896. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Fissural diagrams." Cornell publication, December 1891. (Box 5)
  - _______. "The fundamental principles of anatomical nomenclature." Reprinted from The Medical News, 19 December 1891. (Box 5)
  - _______. "The morphological importance of the membranous or other thin portions of the parieties of the encephalic cavities." Reprinted from The Journal of Comparative Neurology, October 1891. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Neural Terms." Reprinted from The Journal of Comparative Neurology, February 1897. (Box 5)
  - _______. "The paroccipital fissure: should it be recognized and so designated?" Reprinted from Proceedings of the Association of American Anatomists, December 1895. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Revised interpretation of the central fissures of the educated suicide's brain exhibited to the Association in 1894." Reprinted from the Jounral of Nervous and Mental Disease, October 1900. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Some misapprehensions as to the simplified nomenclature of anatomy.´Address of the President of the Association of American Anatomists, 28 December 1898. (Box 5)
  - _______. "What is the morphologic status of the olfactory portion of the brain." Abstract of address given before the American Society of Naturalists, 29 December 1897. (Box 5)
  - Wiley, H. W. "Foods and food adulterants." U.S. Department of Agirculture, Division of Chemistry, Bulletin No. 13, 1893. (Box 5)
  - Willett, E.L. and G.W. Salisbury. "The effect of various diluters, cooling rate, temperature of storage, and some other factors, on the livability of spermatozoa in stored samples of bull semen." Cornell University Agricultural Experiment Station, Memoir 249, November 1942. (Box 5)
  - Williams, Walter Long. "Atresia of the right posterior naris in a mare." Reprinted from the Journal of Comparative Medicine and Veterinary Archives, May 1897. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Azoturia, with strain and atrophy of the great dorsal muscles in a mare." Reprinted from the American Veterinary Review, June 1897. (Box 5)
  - _______. "A clinical study of bovine twins and free martins." Reprinted from the Indian Veterinary Journal, October 1933 (Box 5)
  - _______. "A clinical study of bovine twins and free martins." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, April 1934 (Box 5)
  - _______. Contagious abortion in cattle." Reprinted from the Annual Report of the New York Veterinary College for the Year 1913-1914, 1915. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Diseases interfering with reproduction in cattle." Cornell Reading Course for the Farm: Livestock Series, Lesson 161, September 1921. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Glanders." Montana Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin No. 4, June 1894 (Box 5)
  - _______. "The granular venereal disease and abortion in cattle." Bulletin of the U.S. Department of Agriculture, No. 106, 12 September 1914. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Inhalation Pneumonia." A paper read before the United States Veterinary Medical Association at Nashville, 9 September 1897. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Interesting Cases from the surgical and obstetric clinic, New York State Veterinary College." Reprinted from the American Veterinary Review, June 1898. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Luxation of the metacarpo-phalangeal articulation in a horse." Reprinted from the Journal of Comparative Medicine and Veterinary Archives, July 1897. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Maladie du coit." Reprinted from the American Veterinary Review, n.d. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Notes on the surgery of fistulous withers." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, April 1914. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Notes upon the action of mercurochrome on horses." Reprinted from the North Amercian Veterinarian, [1927]. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Observations on the seminal micropathology of bulls." Reprinted from The Cornell Veterinarian, October 1925. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Die pathologie der fortpflanzung bei unseren haussaugetieren." Reprinted from Tierarztliche Rundschau, October 1932. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Die pathologie der fortpflanzung bei unseren haussaugetieren." Reprinted from Tierarztliche Rundschau, July 1932. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Physiological variations." Reprinted from the Proceedings of the Unites States Veterinary Medical Association, September 1896 (Box 5)
  - _______. "The problem of teratology in clinical veterinary medicine." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, January 1936. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Recollections of, and reflections upon sixty-five years in the veterinary profession." Reprinted from The Cornell Veterinarian, April 1945 and July 1945 (Box 5)
  - _______. "Retained placenta in the cow." Reprinted from The Veterinary Alumni Quarterly, Ohio State University, March 1914. (Box 5)
  - _______. Second Annual Report. Montana Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin No. 8, July 1895. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Some phases of bovine genital infections of possible interest to the medical profession." Reprinted from the American Journal of Obstetrics and Gynecology, November 1922.. (Box 5)
  - _______, Carl W. Fisher, and D.H. Udall. "The spavin group of lameness." Reprinted from the 42nd proceedings of the AVMA, 1906. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Sterility in Cattle." Reprinted from the North American Veterinarian, September 1927/ (Box 5)
  - _______. "Suggestions for the repression of sterility, abortion and mammitis in cows and of white scours in calves." New York State Veterinary College circular No.4, 2nd edition, February 1916. (Box 5)
  - _______. Traumatic pericarditis in a cow: recovery." Reprinted from the Jounral of Comparative Medicine and Veterinary Archives, July 1897. (Box 5)
  - Williamson, F.P. and F.E. Emery. "Tuberculosis and its prevention." North Carolina Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 117, 28 June 1895. (Box 5)
  - Willman, John P, S.A. Asdell and Peter Olafson. "An investigation of the cause of the stiff-lamb disease." Cornell University Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin, No 603, May 1934. (Box 5)
  - Willman, John P, S.A. Asdell and W.A. Hagan. "The stiff-lamb disease."Reprinted from the American Society of Animal Production, January 1932 (Box 5)
  - Wills, John Gordon and Charles Linch. "The retest of reacting cattle." Reprinted from the 22nd Annual Report of the U.S. Live Stock Sanitary Association, 1918. (Box 5)
  - Wilson, H.V. "Formation of the blastopoer in the frog egg." Reprinted from Anatomischer Anzeiger, 1900. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Marine biology at Beaufort." Reprinted from The American Naturalist, 1900. (Box 5)
  - _______. "Notes on a species of pelomyxa. Reprinted from The American Naturalist, 1900. (Box 5)
  - Woods, Charles D. "Poultry investigations at the Maine Agricultural Experiment Station." U.S. Department of Agirculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 90, 1906. (Box 5)
  - Wright, James Homer. "Die Entstehung der Blutplättchen.Reprinted from Virchows Archiv für klinische Medizin, 186.Band. 1906. (Box 5)
  - Wright, Jonathan. "The origin and heredity of matter." Reprinted from the St Louis Medical Review, August-September, 1906. (Box 5)
  - Wright, Norman. "The mechanism of secretion of calcium and phosphorus in milk." Reprinted from the Journal of Agricultural Science, 26 July 1928 (Box 5)
- Y
  - Yard, W. W. "Hog cholera and its control." State of Colorado Bulletin No. 1, ca. 1918. (Box 5)
- Z
  - Zugliani, Jose Affonso. "Do curare como coadjuvante em a narcose dos etilistas inveterados." Reprinted from de Brasil Medico-Cirurgico, February 1948. (Box 5)
- Miscellaneous New York State Department of Health Publications
  - "Annual report of the Division of Laboratories and Research." Extract from Fiftieth Annual Report of the State Department of Health for 1929, 1930. (Box 5)
  - "Cancer: facts which every adult should know." New York State Department of Health, Circular No. 20, 1919. (Box 5)
  - "The conduct of an isolation period for communicable disease in a home." New York State Department of Health, 1919. (Box 5)
  - "Diphtheria." New York State Department of Health, Division of Communicable Diseases, n.d. "Diphtheria: information for parents, physicians and health officers." New York State Department of Health, Circular No. 23, 1919. (Box 5)
  - "The Division of Laboratories and Research: A short account of its history and present status." New York State Department of Health, n.d. (Box 5)
  - "Extract from twenty-ninth annual report." New York State Department of Health, 1908. (Box 5)
  - "Laboratories approved for public health service." New York State Department of Health, 1930. (Box 5)
  - "Measles." New York State Department of Health, Circular No. 17, 1919. (Box 5)
  - "Measles and whooping cough." New York State Department of Health, Division of Communicable Diseases, n.d. (Box 5)
  - "Poliomyelitis, acute anterior: information for parents, physicians and health officers." New York State Department of Health, Circular No. 25, 1920. (Box 5)
  - "Scarlet fever." New York State Department of Health, Division of Communicable Diseases, n.d. (Box 5)
  - "Scarlet fever-scarlatina: information for parents, physicians and health officers." New York State Department of Health, Circular No. 15, 1921. (Box 5)
  - "Smallpox." New York State Department of Health, Circular No. 11, 1919. (Box 5)
  - "Statement in regard to state aid for count and municipal laboratories." New York State Department of Health, February 1924. (Box 5)
  - "Typhoid fever: information for patients, physicians and health officers." New York State Department of Health, Circular No. 16, 1919. (Box 5)
  - "Vaccination: what it is, what it does, what its claims are on the people." New York State Department of Health, 1908 (Box 5)
  - "Vaccination." New York State Department of Health, Circular No. 12, 1919. (Box 5)
  - "Venereal diseases." New York State Department of Health, Circular No. 26, 1917. (Box 5)
  - "Whooping cough: information for parents, physicians and health officers." New York State Department of Health, Circular No. 18, 1919. (Box 5)
- Miscellaneous New York State Department of Farms and Markets Publications
  - "Article 5 of the agricultural law chapter 1 of the consolidated laws relating to diseases of domestic animals." Reprinted from New York State Department of Agriculture Bulletin No. 11, 1909. (Box 5)
  - "The foot and mouth disease in New York State." State of New York, Department of Agriculture, n.d.. (Box 5)
  - "A partial list of owners of pure-bred live stock in New York State." State of New York, Department of Agriculture, Bulletin No. 17, 1910. (Box 5)
  - "Provisions of article IV of the agricultural law relating to diseases of domestic animals." State of New York, Department of Agriculture, 1908. (Box 5)
  - "Rabies." State of New York, Department of Agriculture, 24 October 1908. (Box 5)
  - "Report of the Commission for the Investigation of Bovine Tuberculosis," New York State Commission for the Investigation of Bovine Tuberculosis, March 1915. (Box 5)
  - "Stallion enrollments for the year ending December 31, 1917." State of New York, Department of Farms and Markets, Circular No. 165, 1917. (Box 5)
  - "Summary report of farm bureau work in New York State for the calendar year 1914." Farm Bureaus of New York, Bulletin No. 6, June 1915. (Box 5)
- Miscellaneous United States Department of Agriculture Publications
  - "The control of bovine tuberculosis." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry ,Circular 175, 1911. (Box 5)
  - "Control and eradication of tuberculosis in cattle." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, List No. 1, 1 July 1918. (Box 5)
  - "Crossing improved breeds of swine with the common hogs of Florida." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Circular No. 4, 1895. (Box 5)
  - "Directions for use of blackleg vaccine." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Circular No. 21, 1897. (Box 5)
  - "Directory of the Bureau of Animal Industry." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, 1913. (Box 5)
  - "Eleven miscellaneous papers on animal parisites." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 35, 1902. (Box 5)
  - "How to distinguish the different mosquitoes of North America." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Division of Entomology, Circular No. 40, 1900. (Box 5)
  - "How to select good cheese." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Circular No. 11, n.d. (Box 5)
  - "Investigations concerning bovine tuberculosis." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry Bulletin No. 7, 1894. (Box 5)
  - "Milk as food." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Farmers' Bulletin No. 74, 1908. (Box 5)
  - "Mycotic stomatitis of cattle." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Circular No. 51, 1904. (Box 5)
  - "The Opthalmic Test for Glanders." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, 1914. (Box 5)
  - "Proceedings of a conference of federal and state representatives to consider plans for the eradication of the cattle tick." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 97, 1907. (Box 5)
  - "Regulations concerning cattle transportation." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Order No. 8, 1897. (Box 5)
  - "Regulations governing entrance to the veterinary inspector examination." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Circular No. 150, 1909. (Box 5)
  - "Regulations governing the interstate movement of live stock." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Order No. 263, 1919 (Box 5)
  - "Regulations governing the meat inspection of the United States Department of Agriculture." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Order No. 137, 1906 (Box 5)
  - "Regulations governing the meat inspection of the United States Department of Agriculture, effective April 1, 1908." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Order No. 150, 1908 (Box 5)
  - "Regulations governing the meat inspection of the United States Department of Agriculture, as ammended, effective May 1, 1908." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Order No. 150, 1908 (Box 5)
  - "Regulations governing the meat inspection of the United States Department of Agriculture. U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Order No. 211, 1914 (Box 5)
  - "Regulations governing the meat inspection of the United States Department of Agriculture. U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Order No. 211, revised, 1922. (Box 5)
  - Reports of experiments with various insecticide substances, chiefly upon insects affecting garden crops, made under the direction of the entomologist." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Division of Entomology, Bulletin No. 11, 1886. (Box 5)
  - "Service Announcements." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, No. 30, 1909. (Box 5)
  - "Special report on the market for American horses in foreign countries." U.S. Department of Agriculture, 1898. (Box 5)
  - "State sanitary requirements governing admission of live stock." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, 1911. (Box 5)
  - "Tuberculosis: A plain statement of facts regarding the disease, prepared especially for farmers and others interested in live stock." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Farmers' Bulletin No. 473, 1916. (Box 5)
  - "Tuberculosis in live stock: Detection, control and eradication." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Farmers' Bulletin No. 1069, 1919. (Box 5)
- Miscellaneous United States Department of Public Health Publications
  - Municipal ordinances, rules and regulations pertaining to public hygiene." United States Treasury Department, Public Health and Marine-Hospital Service, Public Health Report No. 70, 1912 (Box 5)
  - Public Health Reports, Volume 26, No. 14 (7 April 1911) (Box 5)
  - "Report of commission of medical officers detailed by authority of the President to investigate the cause of yellow fever." United States Treasury Department, Marine-Hospital Service, 1899. (Box 5)
  - "Yellow fever: its nature, diagnosis, treatment, and prophylaxis and quarantine regulations relating thereto." United States Treasury Department, Marine-Hospital Service, 1899. (Box 5)
  - Venereal disease information. United States Treasury Department, Public Health Service, Vol 12, no. 10 (20 October 1931). (Box 5)
- Miscellaneous
  - United States Bureau of the Census. "Tuberculosis in the United States [ prepared for the International Congress on Tuberculosis, Washington, Fall 1908]. Census Publications on Mortality Statistics, V.S. pamphlet No. 109, ca. 1909. (Box 5)
  - Historia Naturalis Geologia-Zoologia Varia. Catalogue No 96 de la Librarie Scientifique de Jacques Lechevalier. 1922. (Box 5)